To save the future, they must alter the past.
X-Men: Days of Future Past is a action, adventure,
science fiction film directed by Bryan Singer.
The ultimate X-Men ensemble fights a war for the survival of the species across two time periods as they join
forces with their younger selves in an epic battle that must change the past – to save our future.
Logan / Wolverine, played by Hugh Jackman.
Charles Xavier, played by James McAvoy.
Erik Lehnsherr, played by Michael Fassbender.
Professor X, played by Patrick Stewart.
Magneto, played by Ian McKellen.
Raven / Mystique, played by Jennifer Lawrence.
X-Men: Days of Future Past is a 2014 superhero film based on
the Marvel Comics superhero team the X-Men.
It is the seventh in the X-Men film series.
Directed by Bryan Singer and written by Simon Kinberg, the film features an ensemble cast, including Hugh Jackman, James McAvoy, Michael
Fassbender, Jennifer Lawrence, Halle Berry, Anna Paquin, Elliot Page, Peter Dinklage, Ian McKellen, and Patrick Stewart.
The story, inspired by the 1981 Uncanny X-Men storyline "Days of Future Past" by Chris Claremont and John Byrne, focuses on two time periods, with Logan
traveling back in time to 1973 to change history and prevent an event that results in unspeakable destruction for both humans and mutants.
Vaughn had directed X-Men: First Class and was set to return in Days of Future Past but instead
left for Kingsman: The Secret Service and the 2015 version of Fantastic Four.
Singer, who had directed the first two X-Men films, returned as director,
and brought along most of the crew from those productions.
With a budget of $205 million, the film's principal photography began in Montreal, Quebec, in April 2013, and
concluded in August, with additional filming and pick-ups taking place in November 2013 and February 2014.
Twelve companies handled the visual effects.
X-Men: Days of Future Past premiered in New York City on May 10, 2014, and was
theatrically released in the United States on May 23, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received positive reviews from critics, who
deemed it one of the finest in the series.
It grossed $746 million, making it the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2014, and
received an Academy Award nomination for Best Visual Effects.
A sequel, X-Men: Apocalypse was released in 2016.
The film explores themes of 1970s, superhero,
mutant, time travel, based on comic.
The tone is thought_provoking.